A Guide to the Records of the Secretary of Technology, 1997-2006 (bulk 2002-2005)
Library of Virginia
- Series IV: Correspondence & Supporting Documentation, 2002-2005., Extent: 41 boxes. (Box 28-68)
  - Subseries B: Secretary's Correspondence, 2002-2005., 39 boxes (Box 30-68)
    - Sub-Subseries 3: Legislative Files & Information, 1999-2004., 3 boxes (Box 66-68)
      - VITA Reprt on Policies & Procedures, 2004. (Box 68, Folder 9)
      - VITA Special Report, 2004. (Box 68, Folder 10)
- Seires V: Decision Briefs, 2002-2005., Extent: 1 box. (Box 69)
  The Decision Briefs series is housed in one archival folder and is arranged in chronological order. The series contains decision briefs submitted to Governor Mark R. Warner by secretariats for approval. The decision briefs include a synopsis of the request, a recommendation of the secretariat, background information, discussion, and a conclusion. The decision briefs relate to the renewal of a contract for the Relay Center in Norton, Va., the role of the governor as chair of the Southern Technology Council, additional positions for the start-up of the new Virginia Information Technologies Authority (VITA), the proposal of the Southern Technology Council & South Growth Policies Board to develop a brand for the "Technological South," a deficit loan for the Virginia Information Technologies Agency, transitional severance benefits for state employees, the request for the governor to serve as project chairman for the Southern Technology Council's taskforce on venture capital in the south, known as VentureSouth, and the funding for the Virginia Modeling and Simulation Initiative (VIMSIM).
  - Decision Briefs, 2002-2005. (Box 69, Folder 1)
- Series VI: Projects & Studies, 2002-2005., Extent: 5 boxes. (Box 69-73)
  The Projects & Studies series is housed in five archival boxes and is arranged in three subseries. Subseries have been designated for the Center for Innovative Technology, the Department of Information Technology, & the Department of Technology Planning. This series documents special projects managed by the Secretary of Technology. Both the Department of Information Technology & the Department of Technology Planning were superseded by the newly created Virginia Information Technologies Agency in 2003.
  - Subseries A: Center for Innovative Technology (CIT),2002-2005., 4 boxes (Box 69-72)
    The Center for Innovative Technology (CIT) subseries is housed in four archival boxes and is arranged in alphabetical order. This subseries contains correspondence, presentations, press releases, reports, and other sundry items. The subseries documents the work of the Center for Innovative Technology, Virginia's state-chartered nonprofit corporation to enhance federal research funding to Virginia's colleges, universities, & industry, to commercialize intellectual property from universities & laboratories, and promote technology-based economic development. Noteworthy are files related to board meetings, the Governor's Advisory Board for the Virginia Biotechnology Initiative, Higher Education Research Projects, and the Virginia Research & Technology Advisory Council (VRTAC).
    - Board of Directors, 2002. (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Board Meeting, 2002. (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Board Meeting, 2003. (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Board Profiles, 2003. (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Budget Press Release, 2003. (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Building Appraisal, 2002. (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Executive Agreements, 2003. (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - General Assembly Opposition, 2003. (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Governor's Advisory Board for the Virginia Biotechnology Initiative (Folder 1), 2003. (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Governor's Advisory Board for the Virginia Biotechnology Initiative (Folder 2), 2003. (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Governor's Advisory Board for the Virginia Biotechnology Initiative (Folder 3), 2003. (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Higher Education Research Projects(Folder 1), 2005. (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Higher Education Research Projects(Folder 2), 2005. (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Innovative Technology Authority, 2002-2003. (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Higher Education Research Projects(Folder 1), 2005. (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Jobse, Peter, 2002-2003. (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Land Committee 2002. (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Land Use Study 2002. (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Lobbying Efforts 2003. (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous 2002. (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Presentations 2002-2003. (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - President's Briefing 2005. (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Southwest Virginia 2002. (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - STARS Management Group 2003. (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Strategic Plan 2003. (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Strategic Plan 2003. (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Election & Registration Information System (VERIS) 2005. (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Research & Technology Advisory Council (VRTAC) Quarterly Meeting 2005 May 17. (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Research & Technology Advisory Council (VRTAC) Quarterly Meeting 2005 Sept. 20. (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Subseries B: Department of Information Technology (DIT), 2002-2003., 1 box (Box 72)
    The Department of Information Technology (DIT) subseries is housed in one archival box and is arranged in chronological order. This subseries contains correspondence, memorandums, publications, and other sundry items. Included in this subseries are letters & memorandums from Bruce G. Gordon, Acting Director of the Department of Information Technology, and later Cheryl Clark, Director.
    - 2002 January-March 8. (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - 2002 March 11-December. (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - 2003. (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Subseries C: Department of Technology Planning (DTP), 2001-2003., 1 box (Box 73)
    The Department of Technological Planning subseries is housed in one archival box and is arranged in chronological order. This subseries contains correspondence, reports, memorandums, decision papers, and other sundry items. Included are letters & memorandums from N. Jerry Simonoff, Director of the Department of Information Technology, & George C. Newstrom, Secretary of Technology. In addition, there are various procurement requests from the Department of Technology Planning to the Secretary of Technology and requests for staff to attend conferences.
    - 2001. (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - 2002 January-May. (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - 2002 June-December. (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - 2003. (Box 73, Folder 4)
- Series VII: Public Relations, Activities, & Visits, 2002-2005., Extent: 7 boxes. (Box 74-80)
  The Public Relations, Activities, & Visits series is housed in six archival boxes and is arranged in two subseries. Subseries have been designated for Press Clips & Releases and Speeches. This series mainly documents media information about the Secretary of Technology & technology issues and speeches, rather than the planning of public relations, activities, & visits. See Series I: Appointment Calendars for information on public appearances.
  - Subseries A. Press Clips & Releases, 2002-2004., 2 boxes (Box 74-75)
    The Press Clips & Releases subseries is housed in two archival boxes and is arranged chronologically with press clips filed separately from press releases. This subseries documents news clippings & magazine articles related to the appointment of George C. Newstrom as Secretary of Technology, the creation of the Virginia Information Technologies Agency, and technology-related issues in Virginia. The press releases relate to various announcements from the Governor's Office, Virginia's Center for Innovative Technology, and the Secretary of Technology.
    Arranged in chronological order with press clips separated from press releases.
    - Press Clips
      - 2002 January-June (Box 74, Folder 1)
      - 2002 July-December (Box 74, Folder 2)
      - 2003 January-April (Box 74, Folder 3)
      - 2003 May-August (Box 74, Folder 4)
      - 2003 September-November (Box 74, Folder 5)
      - 2004 January-May (Box 74, Folder 6)
      - 2004 June-December (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Press Releases
      - 2003 (Box 75, Folder 1)
      - 2004 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Subseries B: Speeches, 1998-2005., 7 boxes (Box 75-80, 87)
    The Speeches subseries is housed in six archival boxes and is arranged in chronological order, then alphabetically. This subseries documents various speeches made by the Secretary of Technology between 2002 and 2005. In addition, there is background information including articles, publications, phone conversation logs, & correspondence. Noteworthy is Secretary George C. Newstrom's Congressional testimony before the House Select Committee on Homeland Security in 2004. There are also transcripts & drafts of speeches given by the secretary at various technology conferences such as COVITS & NASCIO.
    - 1998
      - Civic.com Magazine (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - 2000
      - Government Technology Magazine (See Oversized) (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - 2002
      - Broadband (Box 75, Folder 5)
      - Digital State 2002 (Box 75, Folder 6)
      - E-Government (Box 75, Folder 7)
      - General (Box 75, Folder 8)
      - Government Technology Magazine (See Oversized) (Box 75, Folder 9)
      - Government Technology Magazine Supplements (Box 75, Folder 10)
      - Governor's Intro (Box 75, Folder 11)
      - Governor's Technology Awards (Box 75, Folder 12)
      - North American High-Tech Convention (Box 75, Folder 13)
      - Richmond Export Import Club (Box 75, Folder 14)
      - Richmond Times-Dispatch (Box 75, Folder 15)
      - Small Business Innovative Research (SBIR) (Box 75, Folder 16)
      - Speech Writers (Box 75, Folder 17)
      - Wilder Commission (Box 75, Folder 18)
      - Wireless Portal (Box 75, Folder 19)
    - 2003
      - Arlington Economic Development Tech Luncheon (Box 75, Folder 20)
      - British-American Business Association Luncheon (Box 76, Folder 1)
      - Broadband (Box 76, Folder 2)
      - Commonwealth of Virginia Innovation Technology Symposium (COVITS) (Box 76, Folder 3)
      - Emerging Leaders Institute (Box 76, Folder 4)
      - General (Box 76, Folder 5)
      - Governing Magazine (Box 76, Folder 6)
      - Government Technology Magazine (See Oversized) (Box 76, Folder 7)
      - Homeland Security (Folder 1) (Box 76, Folder 8)
      - Homeland Security (Folder 2) (Box 76, Folder 9)
      - Indian Institute of technology (Box 76, Folder 10)
      - Industry Advisory Council (Box 76, Folder 11)
      - Information Technology Associaition of America (ITAA) (Box 76, Folder 12)
      - Joint Commission on Technology & Science (JCOTS) (Box 76, Folder 13)
      - Kojo Nnamdi Show (Box 76, Folder 14)
      - Korean Delegation Luncheon (Box 76, Folder 15)
      - National Electronic Commerce Coordinating Council (NECCC) (Box 77, Folder 1)
      - Newstrom, George (Box 77, Folder 2)
      - Old Dominion University (Box 77, Folder 3)
      - Press Inquiries (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Style Weekly (Box 77, Folder 5)
      - Tappahannock/Essex Chamber of Commerce (Box 77, Folder 6)
      - Technology Goddesses: Women in technology (Box 77, Folder 7)
      - TechnoMart (Box 77, Folder 8)
      - Trade (Box 77, Folder 9)
      - Virginia Information Technologies Agency (VITA) (Box 77, Folder 10)
      - Virginia Linked Workforce Showcase (Box 77, Folder 11)
      - Virginia Rankings (Box 77, Folder 12)
      - Website (Box 77, Folder 13)
      - Wireless Technology (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - 2004
      - Accomplishments (Box 77, Folder 15)
      - COVITS Press Contacts (Box 77, Folder 16)
      - Congressional Testimony Before the House Select Committee on Homeland Security (Box 77, Folder 17)
      - Cybersecurity (Box 78, Folder 1)
      - Digital Opportunity Investment Trust (DO IT) (Box 78, Folder 2)
      - Digital State Survey (Box 78, Folder 3)
      - First Robotics Regionals (Box 78, Folder 4)
      - G-Con (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - General (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Government Technology Magazine (See Oversized) (Box 78, Folder 7)
      - Governing Magazine-Public Official of the Year Award (Box 78, Folder 8)
      - Government Technology Magazine (See Oversized) (Box 78, Folder 9)
      - Governor's Priorities (Box 78, Folder 10)
      - Greater Richmond Technology Council (GRTC) (Box 78, Folder 11)
      - Hampton Roads technology Council (Box 78, Folder 12)
      - Huang, Eugene (Box 78, Folder 13)
      - Joint Commission on Technology & Science (JCOTS) (Box 78, Folder 14)
      - Milken Institute (Box 78, Folder 15)
      - NABCA Legal Symposium (Box 78, Folder 16)
      - National Association of State Chief Information Officers (NASCIO), April 25 (Box 78, Folder 17)
      - National Association of State Chief Information Officers (NASCIO), April 26 (Box 78, Folder 18)
      - National Association of State Chief Information Officers (NASCIO)- Award (Box 78, Folder 19)
      - New Century Technology Council (NCTC) (Box 79, Folder 1)
      - Northern Virginia Technology Council (NVTC) (Box 79, Folder 2)
      - Post-Session Speech (Box 79, Folder 3)
      - Public CIO Magazine (Box 79, Folder 4)
      - Rappahannock Community College (Box 79, Folder 5)
      - Spam Speech (Box 79, Folder 6)
      - Style Weekly (Box 79, Folder 7)
      - Technological Innovation/Emerging Trends (Box 79, Folder 8)
      - Telecom Hub Luncheon (Box 79, Folder 9)
      - VITA Accomplishments (Box 79, Folder 10)
      - VITA Chief Information Officer (Box 79, Folder 11)
      - Virginia Geographic Information Network (VGIN) (Box 79, Folder 12)
      - Wilder Commission (Box 79, Folder 13)
    - 2005
      - Government Technology Magazine (See Oversized) (Box 79, Folder 14)
      - Huang, Eugene (Box 79, Folder 15)
      - Northern Virginia Technology Council (NVTC) (Box 80, Folder 1)
      - Press Contacts (Box 80, Folder 2)
      - Technology Councils (Box 80, Folder 3)
      - Website Changes (Box 80, Folder 4)
- Series VIII: Strategic Plan for Technology, 2002-2004., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 80-81)
  The Strategic Plan for Technology series is housed in two archival boxes and is arranged alphabetically. This series documents the development of a Strategic Plan for Technology. The series includes presentations, memorandums, correspondence, talking points, and other sundry items. The series contains a Strategic Planning binder kept by the Secretary of Technology. Also useful are the presentations given by the Secretary of Technology.
  - Certification, 2003. (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Presentations
    - 2002. (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - 2002. (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Strategic Planning Binder
    - Agency Action Plans, 2002. (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Critical Infrastructure Protection, 2004. (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Earth & Environmental Science, 2003. (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Engineering & Materials, 2003. (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Higher Education, 2003. (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Life & Medical Sciences, 2003. (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Small Business Initiative, 2003-2004. (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Research & Technology Advisory Commission (VRTAC), 2003-2004. (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - Talking Points, 2003. (Box 81, Folder 8)
  - Town Hall Meeting Videotape, 2003. (Box 80, Folder 9)
- Series IX: Virginia Information Technologies Agency (VITA), 2002-2005., Extent: 5 boxes. (Box 82-86)
  The Virginia Information Technologies Agency (VITA) series is housed in five archival boxes and is arranged alphabetically. This series documents the Virginia Information Technologies Agency which was created in 2003. The series also documents the Information Technology Investment Board (ITIB) which was created along with VITA to review & prioritize enterprise-wide technology investments across state government. The series includes quarterly reports, plans, proposals, correspondence, and other sundry items. Noteworthy are VITA's final operating plan from 2003, quarterly reports from 2004 to 2005, and the ITIB meeting records.
  - Analysis of the Imagine PA Public Sector ERP Project, 2004. (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Audit Report, 2004. (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Biennial Report on Technology Strategy for the Commonwealth, 2004. (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Business Plan, 2004. (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Cabinet Technology Team for Administration Progress Report, 2004. (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Change Management, 2003. (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia: Enterprise Applications, 2005. (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia: Enterprise Applications
    - Architecture Initiative (Sections 1-8), 2005. (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Architecture Initiative (Sections 9-Appendix C), 2005. (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - Architecture Initiative (Appendix D-F), 2005. (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - PPEA Detailed Proposal, Vol. I (Sections 1-3), 2005. (Box 82, Folder 11)
    - PPEA Detailed Proposal, Vol. I (Sections 3.1-3.3), 2005. (Box 82, Folder 12)
    - PPEA Detailed Proposal, Vol. I (Sections 3.4-6), 2005. (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - PPEA Detailed Proposal, Vol. II (Part 1), 2005. (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - PPEA Detailed Proposal, Vol. II (Part 2), 2005. (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Council on Technology Services (COTS), 2004. (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Council on Technology Services (COTS), 2005. (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Draft Operating Plan (Part 1), 2003. (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - Draft Operating Plan (Part 2), 2003. (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - Employee Dialogue Sessions, 2003. (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - Employee Dialogue Sessions, 2005. (Box 83, Folder 9)
  - Executive Dialogue Meetings, 2003. (Box 83, Folder 10)
  - Final Operating Plan (Part 1), 2003. (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Final Operating Plan (Part 2), 2003. (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - General Assembly Session (Part 1), 2003. (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - General Assembly Session (Part 1), 2003. (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - General Assembly Session (Part 3), 2003. (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Inbound 800 Voice Services, 2003. (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - Information Technology Investment Board (ITIB) 2003.
    - IT Project Review Committee, 2004. (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Legislative Committee, 2004. (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Meeting, 2004 Aug. 11. (Box 84, Folder 9)
    - Meeting, 2004 Oct. 13. (Box 84, Folder 10)
    - Meeting, 2005 Feb. 9. (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Meeting, 2005 Sept. 8. (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Meeting, 2005 Oct. 25. (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Projects Report, 2004. (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Projects Report, 2005. (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Leadership On-boarding
    - Phase 2 Integration Management, 2003. (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Strategic Direction & Operating Manual, 2003. (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - Legislation Tracking, 2004-2005. (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 2003-2004. (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - Project Manager Selection & Training Standard, 2003. (Box 85, Folder 11)
  - Public-Private Education Facilities & Infrastructure Act of 2002, 2003-2004. (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Quarterly Reports, 2004 Apr. 1. (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Quarterly Reports, 2004 July 1. (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Quarterly Reports, 2004 Oct. 1. (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Quarterly Reports, 2005 Jan. 1. (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Quarterly Reports, 2005 Apr. 1. (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Quarterly Reports, 2005 Oct. 1. (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Quarterly Status Report, 2004. (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Talking Points, 2002. (Box 86, Folder 9)
  - Team CGI-AMS Presentation of the Virginia Enterprise Applications Architecture Initiative, 2005. (Box 86, Folder 10)
  - Update, 2003. (Box 86, Folder 11)
  - VITA Bill Signing & Agency Head Meeting, 2003. (Box 86, Folder 12)
- Series X: Virginia Technology Alliance (VTA), 2004-2005., Extent: 1 box. (Box 86)
  The Virginia Technology Alliance (VTA) series is housed in one archival box and is arranged alphabetically. This series documents the Virginia Technology Alliance and its ten regional technology councils. The series includes a report from each technology council in 2005 and general information about the councils.
  - Report, 2005. (Box 86, Folder 12)
  - Technology Councils, 2002-2004. (Box 86, Folder 13)
- Oversized, 2000-2004., Extent: 1 box. (Box 87)
  - Series VII: Public Relations, Subseries B: Speeches.
    - 2000 - Government Technology Magazine (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - 2002 - Government Technology Magazine (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - 2003 - Government Technology Magazine (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - 2003 - Washington Technology Magazine (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - 2004 - Government Technology Magazine (Box 87, Folder 5)